Only
only the top dogs on dog. No fluff, no
fakes on the future lies on. So join the
trend on go.
Welcome to lesson one of our Coach Dog
Spark course. In this lesson, we're
going to look at how you can create a
professional profile to attract clients
to your business.
When developing a professional photo, we
have three options. The first of all, we
have the expensive route, which is to
hire a professional photographer to get
that perfect picture that we want for
our social media and our coach dog
profile. The second option is we can put
a picture of ourselves into chat GPT or
another AI software and ask it to
generate a professional photo with the
right prompt to dress us in the way we
want to dress and how we want to appear
on social media. This looks a little bit
unrealistic. People can pick up on AI
photos. So, we advise against this. What
we advise instead if you don't have the
money and the cash to invest in a
professional photographer is to take a
professional photo in some nice clothes
in a nice position or a nice pose that
you feel comfortable with and then do
some professional editing using AI to
have a perfect profile picture. Let's
take a look at how we can do this third
option in this lesson.
So, this is probably the best way to get
a professional photo for your profile.
As you can see, I just have a standard
background in the back. Now, what we're
going to do is we're going to look for
professional photo. You want to be
either half shot or you want to be a
little bit closer for a head shot. And
you want to be wearing something nice.
It needs to be attractive. It needs to
represent your brand and who you are as
an individual. And simply what we do at
this stage is we get to the point in
which we want to take a picture and we
take the picture. Then what we do is
some editing skills to make it look
professional. The reason why I suggest
doing it this way is because yes you can
get chatpt
whatever AI platform to generate a
picture of you but it does look a little
bit fake. It doesn't look real. This way
it is the real you but with a
professional background. You might want
to employ a photographer or somebody who
knows it. You might want to Google and
look at some poses. You might want to
have a professional side pose. You might
want to cross your arms. But you've got
to think about how you want to look. And
you can do this all from your smartphone
without paying a lot of money for a
photographer. So, let's take a look at
how we then edit this photo that I've
just taken. So, you can have a
professional photo for your Coach dog
profile.
So, here's the photo that I've just
took. As you can see, we've got that
normal background. And what I've done
here is I've uploaded it into the
software Canva. Um, and then I've just
added it to a standard Instagram post
here. What I'm going to do first, I'm
just going to expand this to
the border so it fits.
Okay, give me a second.
So it fits in. So it should cover the
whole canvas. So you can see it covers
the canvas. And if you haven't got
Canber, you can get a free version.
There might be a watermark and certain
features that you can't use, but it is
quite cheap. It's about $1099
a month. So check it out. It's
definitely a tool that we should be
having as a coach for all our content
and all the AI capabilities that it has.
Now, what we're going to do from here to
make it look professional is we're going
to go and click the background remover.
So you click on the picture and you
click background remover. And this is
going to remove the background.
And from here you've got two options.
You've got one that's a little bit
quicker, but the quality that it
produces isn't so great. So the first
one we can do here, I'm going to show
you how to do both. You can click edit,
and then if you look down here, you can
see background generator. So if we click
this, it's going to ask us for a prompt.
And in here we can say um uh please give
me a background
uh office background let's say
when I can type office background
for a professional
photo. Now the the reason why I say this
is not always clear is because the
prompt we have to be really detailed
with our prompt and the Canva prompt is
a little bit clunky. I don't tend to
like how it produces and looks off the
back of this. So, I'll show you. Let's
click generate. This is going to give us
four different options from what I've
put in there in terms of a background.
Let's take a look at what it produces.
It's taking its time. So, there you go.
It's giving me a blurred background
office there. If I want to change it to
that or a clear background. So, it's
given me a couple of different options
that look okay. But what I tend to like
is if I undo that, if it lets me cancel
that and don't give a background. What I
prefer to do is this. So, Canva has good
stock. So, if you go into here, so you
click the elements on the left hand side
panel and if you type in office
and then go to photos, you can actually
choose from a range of offices to set
your background. So, for example, let's
just take this one. And then again, what
you want to do is make sure it covers
the canvas
and then click position and to back. And
that puts it in the back. And then you
can arrange yourself where you want on
that. But that gives you a nice
professional background and a
professional setting. Now, a few things
that I haven't talked about is what
camera you're using. So, you want to
make sure that you've got a camera that
has good quality, that can be seen, that
can be visible. And this isn't the best
photo caption of me, but it's just a
quick demonstration to show you how to
do this. But you got to think about the
quality the photo was taken, the camera
lens that it's taken with because that's
going to include the quality. But
equally, if I wanted, if I just wanted
my head, I can enlarge myself just to
get the head shot. And again, I could
choose a better background. It doesn't
have to be uh in an office. You could
type in um I don't know, think of
somewhere maybe you want a nature
background. Maybe that's your niche and
that's your area. You want a nature
background. So, you want to show that
you're in nature. Again, it's going to
produce up lots of photos. You want to
try and get something that looks a bit
natural. Maybe you want mountains behind
you. Let's see what this looks. I don't
think it's going to look great, but
let's see what it looks like. So, we
delete that. We click the mountains. And
we do the same thing. So, you just
increase it to fit the size. And then
you position it. And you send it to the
back. So, you might want a background of
nature or mountains. But this is your
options. Now, if you also want to put a
little bit of a filter, you can come
down and again, if you click the photo,
click edit. And if you come down, you
can start to click your different
filters. That might make you look a
little bit better. Um, it's up to you
how you want to do this. But you can
play around with different filters and
the intensity of the filter as well, if
you want to make it a little bit softer
or not. But there's lots of editing
tools to make yourself look a little bit
more professional in your photo. Um, and
that's it. That's it in a nutshell. So
that is how you get a professional
photo. Now we do have certain dimensions
that you need to meet. So we do
recommend that you do that in Canva. I'm
going to show how you do that now. So
for example, you want a profile photo to
generally be square. So a,000 by a,000
pixels is generally a great option. So
once you've got it set like this, what
you can do is you can click the resize
button in the top here. You can click
custom size. And here you can type in
a,000 by,000 which will give you good p
pixel quality and make the photo square
which will be a good upload size for
your coach dog profile picture. So I'm
just going to resize this design and not
copy it. And you can see it's made it
into a square within seconds. I just
have to expand the background so it fits
the full square
and then just move myself into the
center. And there you go. You've got a
professional looking photo without
having to go out into nature, without
having to go into the mountains or
having to go to an office to make sure
you've got a nice background. You can
set it and create it yourself. And that
is how you can build a professional
profile photo to attract more clients on
Coach Dog. Thank you for listening.
Only the top dogs on dog. No fluff, no
fakes on the future.
So join the trend on good.